Nathan Acks

IT DIRECTOR → PENETRATION TESTER / ETHICAL HACKER

Nathan Acks has over 20 years of experience in a wide variety of IT disciplines, including systems administration, website design, database administration, vendor and project management, and application development. In 2016 they helped found the IT & Security Team at the Public Interest Network (TPIN), and as its first director oversaw the push to modernize TPIN's IT infrastructure and improve its IT security programs. Nathan is now looking to return to a more hands-on role and build on their IT security experience by beginning a new career in cybersecurity.

nathan.acks@cardboard-iguana.com (720) 806-0007 http://cardboard-iguana.com

Denver, Colorado US

https://github.com/necopinus https://twitter.com/necopinus

EXPERIENCE

The Public Interest Network IT Director Jun 2016 - Present

Founded and oversaw The Public Interest Network's IT & Security team.

- Responsible for writing and maintaining IT- and security-related documentation and training
- Developed a security tier system for offices and staff in order to rationalize existing IT and physical security policies
- Helped craft organization-wide security policies in close cooperation with the Legal team and the President's Office
- Bottom-line responsibility for roll-out, maintenance, security, and support for IT systems used by all staff, including email, user authentication, document management, and custom internal applications
- Developed an internal system for tracking and managing the entire lifecycle for accounts in services managed by the IT & Security team
- Supervised the migration to Google Workspace from a legacy vendor email system
- Supervised the migration to Okta from a legacy LDAP system
- Managed roll-out of two-factor authentication to all full-time staff
- Managed the transition Microsoft 365
- Managed the migration of multiple office-based phone systems to Zoom Phone
- Upgraded and managed office networks across the continental US
- Acted as the technical point of contact for IT-related PCI DSS issues
- Investigated and remediated potential IT security incidents

The Public Interest Network

Manager of Online Outreach Technology Oct 2009 - Jun 2016

Acted as point on data analysis, database development, and IT vendor management for the The Public Interest Network's digital organizing program.

- Responsible for evaluating and developing new organizing tools and reports for the Digital team
- Developed a custom Perl script for generating constituent mass-mailings
- Managed multiple Ubuntu, CentOS, and Arch Linux servers running mission-critical applications such as LDAP/GOsa, MySQL,
 NFS, Git, Postfix, Apache, CiviCRM, and WebGUI
- Responsible for contractor and vendor relations for all Digital team technology, as well as associate budgets
- Oversaw the migration of an in-house constituent relationship management (CRM) and action system to Convio, and then later from Convio to Salsa and MySQL
- Lead a project to integrate vendor CRM databases with a separate system hosted by ROI Solutions
- Wrote and curated a large library of custom SQL and PL/SQL scripts for reporting and data import/export/clean-up
- Aided in the development of content and outreach strategies as part of a rapid-response organizing team
- Managed social media presence for the Recruitment team
- Provided general tech support for my office's staff and maintained the Denver office's network
- Acted as the technical point of contact for PCI DSS and computer security issues

U.S. Anti-Doping Agency

Chaperon

Jun 2009 - Sep 2009

 Supported the work of doping control officers by handling paperwork, monitoring athletes during testing, and providing other services as needed

Equity, LLP

Apartment Manager

Apr 2007 - May 2009

- Performed basic building maintenance and repair including yard work, gardening, and snow removal
- Responsible for on-site security and tenant-landlord relations, including rent collection

Tattered Cover

Retail Manager

May 2008 - Jan 2009

- Managed teams of 3 12 book sellers
- Handled customer complaints, hiring inquiries, and initial trouble-shooting for floor computer systems (Square One, POS, Linux terminals, VoIP telephones, printers, and other hardware)
- Responsible for on-site security (including inventory and cash)
- Regular book seller duties such as customer queries, product stocking, and cash handling

Tattered Cover

Floor Manager

Mar 2008 - May 2008

- Managed teams of 3 12 book sellers
- Handled customer complaints, hiring inquiries, and initial trouble-shooting for floor computer systems (Square One, POS, Linux terminals, VoIP telephones, printers, and other hardware)
- Responsible for on-site security (including inventory and cash)
- Regular book seller duties such as customer queries, product stocking, and cash handling

Tattered Cover

Book Seller

Jul 2007 - Mar 2008

■ Handled customer queries, product stocking, cash handling, and other aspects of floor book sales

University of Colorado, Denver

Computer Lab Assistant

Apr 2005 - Jun 2007

- Tutored students in mathematics and provided test proctoring services
- Administered 35 Windows XP Professional clients and a Windows 2003 file server using Norton Ghost and Faronics Deep Freeze

University of Colorado, Denver

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Dec 2006 - May 2007

- Taught Mathematics for the Liberal Arts including the topics of logic, critical thinking, Venn diagrams, flow charts, units, percentages, scales, compound interest, savings plans and loans, basic statistics, basic probability, basic combinatorics, and exponential growth
- Emphasized the importance of logical quantitative thinking, and how these skills can be integrated into all areas of life

University of Colorado, Denver

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Jul 2006 - Dec 2006

- Taught College Algebra including the topics of lines, circles, functions, polynomials, rational functions, inequalities, complex numbers, exponential functions, logarithmic functions, operations on functions, systems of linear equations, systems of linear inequalities, and matrix algebra
- Emphasized technology-assisted learning with a particular focus on the use of the TI-83 and TI-84 calculators

University of Colorado, Denver

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Dec 2005 - May 2006

- Taught Calculus I recitation including the topics of limits, series, parametric equations, differentiation, simple differential
 equations, and Riemann integration
- Emphasized technology-assisted learning with a particular focus on the use of the TI-83, TI-84, and TI-89 calculators, the Derive 5 software package, and McGraw-Hill's MathZone skills assessment environment.

Budget Car & Truck Rental

Summer Intern

May 2006 - Jul 2006

- Translated a non-linear optimization problem into GAMS code and generated a series of simplified network flow problems from the results
- Verified model correctness by comparing logic and test results with those of an older model written in Fortran 95 using the NETSIDE solver

OAO Technology Solutions

Tape Operator

Jun 2004 - May 2005

- Backed up and restored servers, tracked tapes, and performed weekly and as-needed maintenance on data center tape drives and software for ING Security Life of Denver
- Acted as the on-site backup for the backup administrator

Barnes & Noble

Book Seller

Oct 2004 - Jan 2005

Handled customer queries, product stocking, and other aspects of floor book sales

ImageNative Worlds, Inc.

System Administrator & Developer

Jan 2003 - Jun 2004

- Designed, implemented, and administered the corporate website and the web presence for Cyberpunk the Collectible Card
 Game, including the website, forums, and mailing lists
- Provided systems administration and technical support in a network environment including Windows, Linux, and macOS systems, installed and maintained Apache web servers, MySQL database servers, and a Microsoft Exchange server
- Supervised a team responsible for migrating sales and customer information databases from Microsoft Access to MySQL and scripting reporting queries
- Assisted in the design and implementation of an extensible, plugin-based content management system written in SQL and object oriented PHP

Comcast

Sales Associate

Apr 2003 - Aug 2003

- Verified data and provided sales support to internal business clients
- Produced monthly performance reports and began to design a series of MsSQL/Python scripts to automate the process

University of Colorado, Denver

Computer Lab Assistant

May 2002 - May 2003

- Tutored students in mathematics and physics and proctored tests
- Provided technical expertise and support during deployment of the Cygwin POSIX emulation environment in the Mathematics Education Resource Center (MERC) computer lab

Tattered Cover

Book Seller

May 2002 - Sep 2002

Handled customer queries, product stocking, cash handling, and other aspects of floor book sales

NIST

Intern

Apr 2000 - May 2002

- Used AutoCAD to diagram prototype electrical systems
- Programmed prototype user interfaces and reporting algorithms using Rocky Mountain BASIC

PC City

Technician

Mar 2000 - May 2000

 Diagnosed problems in client workstations, constructed new systems, and configured computer networks using TCP/IP and DHCP

CompUSA

Software Sales

Aug 1999 - Mar 2000

Handled software floor sales and product layout and acted as the de-facto manager of the software department's day-to-day
operations, including decisions about product layout, stocking priorities, and team work-flow

NREL

Summer Intern

Apr 1999 - Aug 1999

Analyzed X-ray diffraction spectra and tested the electrical properties of various laboratory samples, and presented the
results of this research into commercially viable p-type transparent conducting oxides at a National Laboratory System
conference

Colorado School of Mines

Computer Lab Assistant

Oct 1998 - May 1999

 Monitored student use of the Department of Engineering computer lab, providing technical support and policy enforcement as needed

Colorado School of Mines

Office Assistant

Aug 1998 - May 1999

Handled office and database administration for the Department of Engineering

Costco Wholesale

Stocker

Apr 1998 - Aug 1998

Stocked products and handled on-floor customer service

Butterfly Pavilion & Insect Center

Gift Shop Associate

Apr 1996 - Aug 1997

Handled customer queries, product stocking, and other aspects of gift shop sales

Water World

Cachier

Apr 1993 - Aug 1993

Admissions and food service cashiering

SKILLS

PENETRATION TESTING Burp Suite, Kali Linux, Metasploit, Python, Raspberry Pi

CYBERSECURITY Incident Response, PCI DSS, Security Policy

IT OPERATIONS

Bash, Cloud Computing, Computer Networking, Database Administration, Database Design, Documentation, Google Cloud Platform, Google Workspace, Linux System Administration, MySQL, Office 365 Administration, PL/SQL, SQL, Technical Support, Web Servers, Windows Server, Zoom

WEB DEVELOPMENT CSS, Git, GitHub, Jekyll, Netlify, PHP

MANAGEMENT Budgeting, Information Technology Training, Project Management, Vendor Management

VOLUNTEERING

Yak Collective

Yakshaver Apr 2020 - Present

An online space for people interested in collaborative tinkering towards a post-Weirding world.

- Maintained a static website for the organization using GitHub, Netlify, Cloudinary, and IFTTT
- Helped design and implement externally-facing project pages
- Helped set up and maintain a member database using Knack
- Part of the core team responsible for managing the organizational treasury using Gnosis Safe

Colorado Indymedia

Webmaster & Reporter

Apr 2009 - Mar 2013

Independent, volunteer-run news reporting website.

- Maintained an independent media website based on Drupal, performing all necessary maintenance, upgrades, and modifications
- Installed and maintained an Internet-facing web server (Ubuntu LAMP stack), and administered Mailman mailing lists
- Contributed photography and stories

Worldchanging

Contributing Writer Nov 2006 - Jan 2008

A nonprofit dedicated to promoting bright green environmentalism.

• Covered stories on sustainable development and emerging social and technological trends in the Mountain and Southwestern states region

Colorado School of Mines Astronomy Club

Secretary Aug 1998 - May 1999

A student club focused on amateur astronomy.

Designed and coded a small, client-oriented website using HTML

Colorado School of Mines Yearbook

Yearbook Staff Aug 1997 - Apr 1998

Student-run college yearbook.

■ Worked on advertising sales and designed the inside cover and table of contents using Adobe Illustrator

Butterfly Pavilion & Insect Center

Volunteer Docent May 1995 - Aug 1997

The world's first stand-alone, accredited non-profit invertebrate zoo.

- Provided assistance and information to visitors
- Assisted with animal feeding and care

EDUCATION

University of Colorado, Denver Masters Applied Mathematics	Apr 2005 - May 2009
University of Colorado, Denver	Jul 1999 - Dec 2003
Bachelors Theoretical Physics	
Colorado School of Mines	Jul 1997 - May 1999
Front Range Community College	Apr 1998 - Aug 1998
Northglenn High School	Jul 1994 - May 1997
Pecos Junior High School	Jul 1991 - May 1994
Hillcrest Elementary School	Jul 1985 - May 1991

AWARDS

Pre Security Learning Path	Sep 2021
TryHackMe	
Complete Beginner Learning Path	Nov 2021
TryHackMe	
Web Fundamentals Learning Path	Jan 2022
TryHackMe	

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: Native speaker

INTERESTS

PHOTOGRAPHY: Landscape Photography, Urban Photography, Macrophotography, Adobe Lightroom